Guide to the George Mason University Athletic Department records, 1979-2010
George Mason University Libraries
- George Mason University Men's Basketball collection
  - E-Mail from the Office of the Provost, March 29 - 30, 2006 March 29 -30, 2006 (Folder 9, Box 1)
    3 paper printouts of emails from the Office of the Provost regarding Final Four celebrations and congratulations on student enthusiasm and good behavior during the tournament
  - Email From the Office of the President, March 22, 29, 2006 March 22, 29, 2006 (Folder 10, Box 1)
    Two emails sent from the Office of the President regarding the NCAA tournament
  - Information on the Web of GMU Alumni Association March - April, 2006 (Folder 11, Box 1)
    Paper printouts of Mason Alumni information regarding men's basketball
  - The Mason Gazette March - April, 2006 (Folder 12, Box 1)
    Paper printouts of Mason Gazette articles about the men's basketball season. Articles printed out from gazette.gmu.edu
  - Expulsion - March 27, 2006 March 27, 2007 (Folder 13, Box 1)
    Satirical newspaper with the headline "Goooo Mason Go Clap Clap Clap."
  - Broadside - Coverage of NCAA Tournament March - April, 2006 (Folder 14, Box 1)
    George Mason University student newspaper Broadside's coverage of the NCAA tournament
  - GMU Basketball Digital Memory Bank 2006 (Folder 15, Box 1)
    Two flyers for hoops.gmu.edu
  - Patriot Pride, Men's and Women's Basketball Practice and Academic Facility (Folder 16, Box 1)
    Brochure regarding donations for the new men's and women's basketball practice and academic facility
  - Mason's Final Four Celebration - Invitation and Program May 2, 2006 (Folder 17, Box 1)
    Invitation, program, and insert for the official Patriot Club Final Four Celebration held at the Patriot Center on May 2, 2006. The insert features a bio on the emcee for the evening, NBC News 4's Sports Director George Michael.
  - 2005-06 George Mason Men's Basketball Program 2005 (Folder 18, Box 1)
    Media guide for the 2005-06 season featuring team and staff profiles, statistics, athletic history and opponent profiles.
  - The Patriot Club Green Coat Society - Brochure (Folder 19, Box 1)
    Brochure regarding donations to Mason athletics
  - Mason Spirit - Spring 2006 2006 (Folder 20, Box 1)
    Alumni magazine featuring several articles on men's basketball
  - "Patriots Hold Five of a Kind" - Washington Post 2006 (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - "Mason Students Ready for Final Four" - DC Examiner 2006 (Folder 22, Box 1)
    Article by Michael Zwelling for the DC Examiner
  - "U-Conn Knows GMU Came Out of Nowhere" - Washington Post March 26, 2006 (Folder 23, Box 1)
    Article by Dan Steinberg for the Washington Post
  - "Magic Carpet Ride Flies On" - Washington Post March 25, 2006 (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - "A New Order on the Court" - Washington Post March 24, 2006 (Folder 25, Box 1)
    Article by Fred Bowen for the Washington Post
  - "George Mason as Hickory High, with Jim Larranaga as Norman Dale" - Washington Post 2006 (Folder 26, Box 1)
    Photograph from the Washington Post
  - "NC Turned on Its Heels - Another Crasher" - The Telegraph March 20, 2006 (Folder 27, Box 1)
    Article in New Hampshire newspaper The Telegraph
  - "Larranaga Relishes Mason's Ride" - The Telegraph March 28, 2006 (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - "Giant Slayers" - The Telegraph March 27, 2006 (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - "Great Moments" - The Telegraph March 27, 2006 (Folder 30, Box 1)
    Article from New Hampshire newspaper The Telegraph
  - "George Mason Proves its Worth, Enters Elite" - The Telegraph March 25, 2006 (Folder 31, Box 1)
    Article by Howard Fendrich in New Hampshire newspaper The Telegraph
  - "One for the History Books" and "Patriots Aren't Afraid of Heights" - Washington Post March 28, 2006 (Folder 32, Box 1)
    Two articles from the Washington Post by Thomas Boswell and Dan Steinberg, respectively.
  - "3 North Carolina vs 11 George Mason" - Washington Post March 19, 2006 (Folder 33, Box 1)
    Article by Camille Powell in the Washington Post
  - Basketball Cartoon - Washington Post 2006 (Folder 34, Box 1)
    Basketball cartoon by Tom Toles in the Washington Post
  - "George Mason is a Giant-Killer" - Washington Post March 27, 2006 (Folder 35, Box 1)
    Article by Liz Clarke in the Washington Post
  - 2005-06 Basketball Fan Guide - Colonial Athletic Association 2005 (Folder 36, Box 1)
  - 2006-07 George Mason Basketball Season Ticket Information 2006 (Folder 37, Box 1)
    Brochure
  - Sticker: "Go Mason - The Slipper Fits" ca. 2006 (Folder 38, Box 1)
    Sheet of basketball themed stickers
  - "Mason Magic Isn't Rocket Science" - Washington Post March 30, 2006 (Folder 1, Box 2)
    Article by Neil Irwin in the Washington Post
  - Brion's Grille - GMU Men's and Women's 2005-06 Basketball Schedule 2005 (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - "Guillotine The Gators" - Free T-Shirt Flyer 2006 (Folder 3, Box 2)
    Color flyer advertising an offer to get a free "Guillotine the Gators" t-shirt at the Mason campus store
  - 2006 NCAA Men's Basketball Tickets March 24 - April 3, 2006 (Folder 4, Box 2)
    Tickets for the NCAA Sweet Sixteen, Elite Eight, Final Four, and Championship games of the tournament. Also included is a ticket pack cover and an admission ticket to Hoop City.
  - Embossed Mason Patriots Envelope January 7, 2006 (Folder 5, Box 2)
    Limited-edition color embossed envelope bearing a cancellation stamp of the Mason Patriots logo. The envelope, stamped at Fairfax Station, VA on April 7, 2006 was part of the citywide celebration for the Patriots' tournament run.
  - Parade Sponsored by the City of Fairfax Celebrating Mason Madness - Flyer April 7, 2006 (Folder 6, Box 2)
    Flyer for a parade sponsored by the City of Fairfax honoring Mason's Final Four tournament run.
  - "Mason Ousts 2005 Champ No.3 UNC" - Baltimore Sun March 20, 2006 (Folder 7, Box 2)
    Article by Skip Myslenski for the Baltimore Sun
  - Washington Post - April 1, 2006 April 1, 2006 (Folder 8, Box 2)
    Washington Post newspaper featuring several articles on the George Mason Patriots
  - "Mason Out of Magic" - Washington Post April 2, 2006 (Folder 9, Box 2)
  - "Final Four Cinderella Men" - Indianapolis Star April 1, 2006 (Folder 10, Box 2)
    Special NCAA Final Four tournament section in the Indianapolis Star
  - "Four Real, Stunner: No.11 Seed George Mason's Improbability Run Continues with OT Victory Over No.1 Seed UConn" - The Express March 27, 2006 (Folder 11, Box 2)
    Cover article in Washington Post Express
  - Party City Coupon for 25% Discount for all GMU Students and Faculty for When the Team Wins the Championship 2006 (Folder 13, Box 2)
    Flyer from Party City congratulating Mason on making it to the Final Four, as well as offering Mason students and faculty a discount on party supplies.
  - 2006 Final Four Indianapolis Program 2006 (Folder 14, Box 2)
    Official 2006 NCAA Final Four program
  - 2006 Final Four Indianapolis Program 2006 (Folder 15, Box 2)
    Official 2006 NCAA Final Four Program
  - News Conference Name Plates 2006 (Folder 16, Box 2)
    NCAA news conference name plates for Jordan Carter and Sammy Hernandez
  - Sports Illustrated, March 27, 2006 "Sweet Surprises" March 27, 2006 (Folder 17, Box 2)
    Sports Illustrated magazine featuring Lamar Butler on the cover
  - NCAA National Semifinals Scorecard April 1, 2006 (Folder 18, Box 2)
    Scorecard for the NCAA Final Four games in Indianapolis, IN on April 1, 2006.
  - Crowne Plaza Information Packet 2006 (Folder 19, Box 2)
    Information packet for the hotel the Mason Patriots stayed at during the NCAA Final Four tournament in Indianapolis
  - "Patriots are Gutsy - Even to Packer" - Washington Post March 28, 2006 (Folder 20, Box 2)
    Article by Rick Snider in the Washington Post
  - Patriots Run to Final Four - Season Review DVD (flyer) 2006 (Folder 21, Box 2)
    Flyer advertising pre-orders for the Mason Patriots men's basketball 2005-06 season review dvd
  - Sweet Sixteen Parties March 2006 (Folder 22, Box 2)
    Two flyers for NCAA Sweet Sixteen parties
  - George Mason University Day Proclamation: County of Fairfax, VA March 24, 2006 (Folder 23, Box 2)
    Proclamation by the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors designating Friday, March 24, 2006 as George Mason University Day. Document contains the signature of Gerald E. Connolly, Chairman of the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors and is dated March 24, 2006.
  - Certificate of Recognition, County of Fairfax, May 15, 2006 May 15, 2006 (Folder 24, Box 2)
    Certificate of Recognition presented to the George Mason University Men's Basketball Team by the County of Fairfax. Document contains the signature of Gerald E. Connolly, Chairman of the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors and is dated May 15, 2006.
  - 2005-06 Men's Basketball Season Souvenirs 2005 - 2006 (Box 3)
    The souvenirs included in this box are: NCAA Final Four ticket holders with lanyards (2), Coach Larranaga music box, George Mason "We Believe" cup, "Go Mason!" buttons (2), Mason Patriots 2006 Final Four badge and lanyard, Mason Patriots temporary tattoos (3), "Larranaga Special" whistles (3), green and yellow pom-pom, and "Go Mason!" thundersticks (2)
  - NCAA 2006 Tournament T-Shirts and Small Mason Patriots Posters 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    T-Shirts: Sweet Sixteen, Elite Eight, 2 different Final Four shirts. Posters: School of Management "Heart" Patriots, Mason Madness (2), and Go Mason (3)
  - 2005-06 Men's Basketball Season and Tournament Run oversize materials 2005-06 (Oversize 1)
    Oversized materials related to the 2005-06 basketball season: Washington Post printing plate from March 27, 2006, Fairfax commuter bus "Go Patriots" sign, community signed bus banners (3), and large Mason Patriots posters (5)